Finding aid for the J. Paul Getty Museum Getty Villa Public Event Recordings, 2006-2018 IA20035
Institutional Records and Archives
- 2011 Events
  Access copies of recordings on discs must be created prior to use. To request access, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2011.IA.02. Please note reformatting may take up to eight weeks.
  - "A Formative Landscape (or Why the Greek Islands Are of Such Importance to Us)" lecture by Nigel McGilchrist, January 13, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
  - "Watching the Fighters: The Roman Fascination with Gladiators" lecture by Garrett Fagan, February 2, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
  - "Sculpting Aphrodite: Praxiteles, Phryne, and the Knidia" lecture by Andrew Stewart, February 24, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
  - "The Revolutionary Architecture of the North Baths at Morgantina, Sicily" lecture by Malcolm Bell and Sandra Lucore, March 2, 2011
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
    - Webcast
  - "Traveling through Biblical Lands: The Dream and the Reality" lecture by Kathleen Stewart Howe, March 26, 2011; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
  - Public reading of Homer's Iliad, April 30, 2011; (set of 3 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
  - "Restoring Ancient Bronzes in the Nineteenth Century" workshop, May 6, 2011
    - Event recording, (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
    - Ephemera (Box 2011.IA.02-04)
  - "Exhibition and Experiment: A History of the Royal Bourbon Museum" lecture by Andrea Milanese, May 5, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
  - "Uncorking the Past: Ancient Ales, Wines, and Extreme Beverages" lecture by Patrick McGoven, June 4, 5, 2011
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
    - Webcast
  - "The Holy Land in the 19th-century Imagination" panel discussion with Burke O. Long, Nitza Rosovsky, and Neil Silberman, moderated by Kathleen Stewart Howe, June 15, 2011; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "The Legacy of Ancient Roman Gardens at the Getty Villa" lecture by Patrick Bowe, June 23, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "Dining with Caesar: Food and Power in Ancient Rome" lecture by Andrew Dalby, July 14, 15, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "After Euripides: A Conversation with Anne Bogart,", October 1, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "Alchemy's Origins in Late Antiquity: Philosophical Crafts and Crafty Philosophers" lecture by Lawrence Principe, October 6, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "The Curious Case of the Octagonal Intaglios: A Possible New Gem Workshop in Central Turkey" seminar by Andrew Goldman and Gertrude Platz-Horster, October 13, 2011; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "What to Do with a Wonder of the World? The Puzzle of Petra" lecture by Susan Alcock, October 27, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "Sex Sells, but Who's Buying? Erotic Imagery on Athenian Vases" lecture by Kathleen Lynch, October 20, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "Picasso's Classic Realisms: Negotiating the Terms of a Relationship" lecture by Christopher Green, November 3, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
  - "Antiquity in the Twentieth Century: Modern Art and the Classical Vision" symposium, November 4, 2011
    - Event recording, (set of 3 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-03)
    - Ephemera (Box 2011.IA.02-04)
  - "Penelope in Persepolis" seminar by Tonio Hölscher, November 10, 2011; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2011.IA.02-05)
  - "Luxury Living in Late Roman Sicily: The Villa at Piazza Armerina" lecture by Roger Wildson, November 30, 2011; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-05)
- 2012 Events
  Access copies of recordings on discs have been created. To request access, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2014.IA.11. For February events, use accession number 2012.IA.29.
  - "New Faces from Egypt: Roman Panel Paintings" lecture by Thomas F. Mathews, February 11, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2012.IA.029-02)
  - "Unearthing Agamemnon's City: The Lower Town of Mycenae" lecture by Chrisofilis Maggidis, February 23, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2012.IA.029-03)
  - "Playing with Eros: Riddles and Rhymes" lecture by Christine Kondoleon, April 19, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Underwater Archaeology off Sicily: Rewriting Naval Warfare in the Third Century B.C." lecture by Jeffrey G. Royal, April 25, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Who Made Etruscan Art? Patronage and Production in Early Italy" lecture by Gregory Warden, May 3, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Aphrodite's Scent and the Essence of Life" lecture by Maria Rosaria Belgiorno, June 21, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Drinking in the Greek Manner: A Brief History of the Symposion" lecture by Oswynn Murray, July 21, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Beautiful Evil: The Challenge of Helen of Troy" lecture by Ruby Blondell, September 15, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Living in Roman Luxury: Terrace House 2 in Ephesus" lecture by Sabine Ladstaetter, October 20, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Pompeii on Display: Disaster into Art" lecture by Kenneth Lapatin, October 24, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "How to Win an Election: An Ancient Guide for Modern Politicians" lecture by Philip Freeman, October 27, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Life and Afterlife: Wall Paintings in Ancient Macedonian Tombs" lecture by Olga Palagia, November 8, 2012; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
  - "Pompeii: Fascination and Fantasy" lecture by Kenneth Lapatin, moderated by Victoria C. Gardner Coates, Shelley Hales, and John Seydl, November 17, 2012; (2 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-02)
- 2013 Events
  Access copies of recordings on discs have been created. To request access, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2014.IA.11.
  - "Saving Herculaneum: The Challenges of Archaeological Conservation" lecture by Andrew Wallace-Hadrill, January 16, 2013; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "Leisure, Commerce, and Tragedy in the Villa of Oplontis near Pompeii" lecture by John C. Clarke, February 23, 2013; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "At the Sicilian Table" lecture by John Wilkins and Sally Grainger, July 20, 2013; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "Defying Zeus to Help Humans: What Was Prometheus Thinking?" lecture by Mark Griffith, September 21, 2013; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "The Cyrus Cylinder: The Discovery and Creation of an Icon" lecture by John Curtis, October 2, 2013; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "Cyrus the Great and the Persian Empire: Perspectives from Antiquity to Today" symposium, October 27, 2013 (Box 2014.IA.11-01)
    - Event recording, (3 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-04)
    - Ephemera (Box 2014.IA.11-04)
  - "Authority and Autonomy in the Achaemenid Persian Empire" lecture by Elspeth Dusinberre, November 2, 2013; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
- 2014 Events
  Access copies of recordings on discs in accession 2014.IA.11 have been created. To request access, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2014.IA.11. To request access to MP3 recordings, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2015.IA.50.
  - "Power, Prosperity, Philosophy: Roman Villas and the Men Who Built Them" lecture by Guy Metraux and Jeffrey Fish, January 16, 2014; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "Tiberius to Nero: Roman Emperors on the Stage and Screen" lecture by Ronald Mellor, February 19, 2014; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "The Greek East under Rome: Art and Cultural Interaction" lecture by Roland Smith, March 19, 2014; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "Tales of Byzantium from Greece" lecture by Maria Andreadaki-Vlazaki, April 9, 2014; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "Heaven and Earth: Perspectives on Greece's Byzantium" symposium, May 2-3, 2014; (2 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-03)
  - "What Happened to Local Traditions of Art in Roman Britain?" lecture by Susan Walker, May 21, 2014; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2014.IA.11-06)
  - "Lucretius and the Toleration of Intolerable Ideas" lecture by Stephen Greenblatt, June 5, 2014; (MP3 file)
  - "At the Byzantine Table: Greek Traditions, Roman Tastes" lecture and dinner, July 19, 2014; (2 MP3 files)
  - "Performing Persia: Cultural Exchange and Visual Power in Aeschylus's Persians" lecture by Rebecca Kennedy, September 13, 2014; (MP3 file)
  - "Alice Oswald: In Light of Homer's Odyssey" lecture by Alice Oswald, October 16, 2014; (MP3 file)
  - "Baths, Temples, and Mosaics: Unearthing a Roman-Era City in Western Turkey" lecture by Michael Hoff, October 18, 2014; (MP3 file)
  - "Berthouville Treasure and Roman Silver Colloquium,", October 28, 2014; (MP3 file)
  - "Dynasty and Destiny in Imperial Rome: The Augustan Experiment and Its Legacy" lecture by John Pollini, October 29, 2014; (MP3 file)
  - "Graves, Archives, and Glue: Stories behind the Funerary Vases of Dangerous Perfection" panel discussion, November 20, 2014; (MP3 file)
- 2015 Events
  To request access to MP3 recordings, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2015.IA.50.
  - Bacchus Uncorked series:
    - "Travels with Bacchus: How an Enigmatic Wine-God Came to France" lecture by Albert Leonard, Jr., July 11, 2015; (MP3 file)
    - "Vinum, Vidi, Vici: Wine, Culture, and Colonialism in Ancient Gaul" lecture by Michael Dietler, July 18, 2015; (MP3 file)
  - The Villa Council Presents series:
    - "Conflict Resolution and its Discontents in Classical Athens" lecture by Edith Hall, June 28, 2015; (MP3 file)
  - "Excavating a Mycenaean Palace near Sparta" lecture by Adamantia Vasilogamvrou, January 14, 2015; (MP3 file)
  - "Amazons: Warrior Women of the Ancient World" lecture by Adrienne Mayor, February 26, 2015; (MP3 file)
  - "Imagery and Identity: The Monumental Vases of Ancient Apulia" lecture by Thomas H. Carpenter, March 5, 2015; (MP3 file)
  - "Death Salon Getty Villa: From Ancient Necropolis to L.A.'s Metropolis" panel discussion with Eric Bruehl, Caitlin Doughty, Jonathan Gold, Paul Koudounaris, Judy Melinek, Lisa Pieraccini, Megan Rosenbloom, David Saunders, Marie Svoboda, and Sarah Elizabeth Troop, April 26, 2015; (3 MP3 files)
  - "Gifts for the Gods: The Art of Devotion in Roman Gaul" lecture by Kimberly Cassibry, May 30, 2015; (MP3 file)
  - "The Mildenhall Treasure: Fine Dining in Roman Britain" lecture by Richard Hobbs, June 7, 2015; (MP3 file)
- 2016 Events
  To request access to MP3 recordings, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2016.IA.52.
  - Bacchus Uncorked series:
    - "Vines and Volcanoes: Greeks, Romans and Wine in Ancient Italy" lecture by Paul Roberts and Diego Meraviglia, July 16, 17, 2016; (MP3 file)
  - "The Acropolis of Athens: The Untold Story" lecture by Thomas W. Gallant, January 21, 2016; (MP3 file)
  - "Our Presidents' Gifts: The Role of Greek Antiquities in Greek-U.S. Political Relationships after World War II" lecture by Athanasio "Nassos" Papalexandrou, February 27, 2016; (MP3 file)
  - "Water and Power: Roman Aqueducts as Monuments and Models" lecture by Peter Aicher, March 6, 2016; (MP3 file)
  - "Roman Mosaics: Evolution, Imagery, and Regional Characteristics" lecture by Demetrious Michaelides, June 16, 2016; (MP3 file)
  - "Stone Pixels: Mosaics Then and Now" lecture by Will Wootton, July 9, 2016; (MP3 file)
  - "Rediscovering the Classical Tradition in Southern California" lecture by Peter Holiday, October 5, 2016; (MP3 file)
  - "The Palmyra Portrait Project: Preserving Cultural Heritage in a Time of Conflict" lecture by Rubina Raja, October 22, 2016; (MP3 file)
  - "A Prince of Pylos: The Tomb of the Griffin Warrior" lecture by Sharon Stocker and Jack Davis, November 6, 2016; (MP3 file)
- 2017 Events
  To request access to MP3 recordings, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2017.IA.91.
  - Bacchus Uncorked series:
    - "The Past on Tap: Feasts and Fermented Brews in Ancient Europe" lecture and tasting with Bettina Arnold and Mark Keene, July 15, 16, 2017; (2 MP3 files)
  - The Villa Council Presents series:
    - "The Quality of Mercy in Imperial Rome, Imperial America, and Mozart's La Clemenza di Tito" lecture by Peter Sellars, April 30, 2017; (MP3 file)
  - "Planting for Power: The Elite Gardens of Ancient Rome" lecture by Annalisa Marzano, March 18, 2017; (MP3 file)
  - "The Ark before Noah" lecture by Irving Finkel, April 1, 2017; (MP3 file)
  - "Colm Tóibín: House of Names" reading by Colm Tóibín, May 20, 2017; (MP3 file)
  - "Beyond the 1%: How Everyday Romans Lived" lecture by Jeremy Hartnett, June 11, 2017; (MP3 file)
  - "The Virtues of Violence: Amphitheaters, Gladiators and the Roman System of Values" lecture by Kathleen M. Coleman, June 17, 2017; (MP3 file)
  - "Euripides's Iphigenia and the Downfall of Athens" lecture by Nicholas Rudall, September 9, 2017; (MP3 file)
  - "Making Athens Great (Again?): Modern Lessons from the Age of Pericles" lecture by Loren J. Samons II, October 25, 2017; (MP3 file)
- 2018 Events
  To request access to MP3 recordings, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2018.IA.81.
  - "Thinking Like a Roman: How to Renew America's Polarized Landscape" lecture by Joy Connolly, February 24, 2018; (MP3 file)
  - "Love Her to Death...and Back: The Enduring Myth of Orpheus and Eurydice" lectures and musical performance with Mary Louise Hart, David Saunders, Stacy C. Brightman, Mitchell Morris, James Conlon, Richard Seaver, Jeremy Frank, Emma-Grace Dunbar, and Sarah Reynolds, March 11, 2018; (2 MP3 files)
  - "Cicero on Friendship: Ancient Wisdom for Modern Times" lecture by Philip Freeman, October 21, 2018; (MP3 file)